(man) Previously on "Prison Break":
I didn't kill him.
- The evidence says you did.
- I was set up.
Put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
you see the inside of a cell.
- I'm looking for Burrows.
- (Sucre) Man killed the VP's brother.
- Why do you want to see him?
- He's my brother.
- I'm getting you out.
- Impossible.
Not if you designed the place.
- You've seen the blueprints.
- Better.
I've got 'em on me.
- You find out who's trying to bury him.
- Nobody is.
The evidence was cooked.
- There's a lawyer poking around.
- Anyone that's a threat is expendable.
- I'm gonna kill that scum.
- You kill him, you kill our ticket out of here.
- Where's Maricruz?
- She's with me now.
Fish, I gotta be back in.
Nick, Project Justice. My boss may not think
Lincoln's case is worth looking into, but I do.
When do we get started?
This wall is just the beginning.
There's a lot of real estate
in between here and the outside.
That is a transfer request. Michael Scofield
is getting shipped out tomorrow.
- About your transfer request for Scofield.
- More specifically, why you denied it.
Look, Mr Kellerman, do I come to your house
and tell you where to put your furniture?
- We're just asking for professional courtesy.
- A federal courtesy in a state penitentiary.
Most people would be happy
to have a body taken off their hands.
These men are my responsibility.
From the minute they walk in
to the time they've paid their debt to society,
I'm responsible.
Unless he's done something
I don't know about,
he is gonna stay here at Fox River
under my watch.
Mr Pope, in our line of work,
just about everyone has done something
that someone doesn't know about.
- What's this?
- Right now, just a piece of history.
Whether it becomes a current event,
now, that's up to you.
My wife already knows about Toledo.
Does she really?
You're a smart man, Warden.
I'm sure you can find a reason
Scofield's presence is no longer required
at this particular correctional facility.
I need some more PVC here, boss.
- Boss?
- Sure thing, Burrows.
I don't wanna check for splinters.
I want every piece accounted for.
Sure.
I got a ripped fertilizer bag inside.
Hey, you!
You!
Get in there and clean it up before this whole
place starts smelling like San Juan.
(mutters to himself)
OK, he's on his way. Do you mind telling me
what this is all about?
These are the guys we're breaking out with.
I don't think so, fish.
That was not our agreement.
I'm not gonna work with this crazy rhino.
- Keep pushing it, John.
- Yeah, I keep pushing it, you know. Huh?
What's your deal, man?
Touch my brother again and I'll show you.
Brother? Your brother?
We've got a few minutes. Are we gonna spend
'em spitting on each other or talk business?
The reason we're all here today
is we have a decision to make.
English, Fitz, or Percy.
If we're gonna pull this off,
we need to take one of them out.
And you want us to tell you which one?
I just want you to help me get to them.
I'll take it from there.
- You're crazy.
- All I need is five minutes.
- You won't get five seconds.
- I thought you had everything worked out.
We're not breaking out of a Jamba Juice.
It's gonna take more than digging a few holes.
There are eyes, ears, dots that couldn't be
connected from the outside.
- And English, Fitz or Percy?
- One of those dots.
And how exactly
are you supposed to pull this off?
With a little help from my friends.
Sucre, hold up. Scofield, you've got company.
Why do I get the feeling that there's more
to you than meets the eye, Scofield?
Anything you wanna tell me?
Some other reason you're in here
besides holding up a bank?
- You're being transferred.
- What?
We're moving you over to Statesville.
- You can't do that.
- Yes, I can. I'm the boss here.
This is my house.
- Three weeks.
- What for?
Lincoln Burrows.
He's being executed in three weeks.
I'm aware of that. What's that to you?
He's my brother.
When I knew I was being sent to prison,
my attorney petitioned the DOC.
- So you could be near him.
- That's right.
Don't take that away from me.
Not until it's over.
I'm not the one behind the transfer.
You're up against much bigger fish than me.
I'll arrange for you to say goodbye.
You ship out tomorrow.
(faint organ music)
I'm going into the walls,
see if I can access the roof.
Were you gonna tell me about the transfer?
- I'm taking care of it.
- You're taking care of it?
Sounds to me like you're reaching.
Maybe. A little.
A little.
I'd made my peace, then you give me the one
thing a man in my situation shouldn't have.
- Hope. And now that's gonna be taken away.
- Don't do this, Linc.
I got three weeks.
What do you want me to do?
(boy) Come on, Michael.
- Bring her back.
- You know I can't do that.
But, look, there's some stuff that I can do.
It's not gonna be the same,
but we're gonna figure it out.
And no matter what,
it's still gonna be me and you.
OK, but what if something happens to you?
You just have a little faith.
Just have a little faith.
(Nick) If we believe Lincoln, this tape is a lie.
- It has to be.
- But you saw it. It's all there.
But maybe what we're looking for
is what's not there.
- OK. Steadman. See, what's he looking at?
- A car? A pedestrian?
(Nick) His eye line is high.
He's looking into the camera.
He might as well be saying "cheese".
- Now he just sits there.
- For 10, 15 seconds, as if he was...
- Waiting for someone.
- Right.
There. That's a nine millimetre.
Shouldn't there be a kick?
- Lincoln's pretty strong.
- Yeah, but strong enough to bury a recoil?
Now, you shoot someone,
supposedly for revenge.
Do you take the time to go in and hit
the glove box? Or get the hell out of there?
Feds said he was trying
to make it look like a robbery.
Look. Look at Lincoln's angle
as he leaves the frame.
Mm.
He walks away from the car.
Now, this guy, who conveniently hides his
face from the camera, comes back in. Why?
To explain the bloody pants they'd already
planted in his apartment. Nick, this is great.
- Who shall we go to?
- Nobody. Yet.
To the unbiased eye, we're backing a horse
that died in the gate. A lot of conjecture.
We don't have anything.
We need some evidence.
Look, if Lincoln didn't fire this gun,
somebody with serious skills
worked on this to prove he did.
Fine, but how do we prove that?
- I know a guy.
- You know a guy?
Yeah, I know a guy.
Thanks.
We need to have a powwow. There's been talk
about you packing your bags.
Don't believe everything you hear.
I'm not going anywhere.
I have a really hard time trusting you, fish.
The important thing
is that we stay on schedule.
- Yeah? English, Fitz and Percy?
- English, Fitz or Percy.
Wanna know which one we should take out?
With all due respect, I don't need opinions.
I need answers.
The warden leaves at five tonight,
so by five after five we need that key.
And how is this key
gonna give you the answers?
I'll worry about that.
Worry about getting the key.
Hey. This key better be worth it.
Understand?
Afternoon, Mr Scofield.
I need to know
if there's a way to block a transfer.
- There's about 50 ways.
- All right. I'll take the quickest.
You file a motion for what they call
an interlocutory injunction.
- How long does that take?
- How fast can you write?
A man can claim almost anything
violates his constitutional rights.
Environmental issues, allergies,
religious requirements - take your pick.
- What if they don't buy it?
- They're required to hear your motion.
Till they do, you can't be transferred.
Hell, they've been trying to move
my tired, grey behind for ten years.
God bless the American legal system.
Why do you want to stay in here so badly?
There's someone here
I can't bear to leave behind.
I guess that means
we've got something in common.
- The state's requiring a physical for Burrows.
- You heard the news?
- No, what?
- They're brothers.
- Who?
- Burrows and Scofield.
Michael Scofield?
Heard it from one of the COs over in Gen Pop.
He didn't say anything about it?
No.
It must be hard to be so close to your brother
and not be able to do anything to help him.
- What's this?
- A little bathroom reading.
- Westmoreland again?
- Scofield. He's blocking his transfer.
Even if the motion is denied,
it's gonna take 30 days to process.
And that means...
All right, I'm going in.
I'm gonna need your help.
In in? Now? I thought you were waiting till...
I need to make sure I know how I'm getting
up there so when the time comes...
In case you didn't notice, the lights are all on.
You've got a live studio audience, fish.
How are you gonna get around that?
Don't we have some laundry to do?
Just to be clear,
I ain't touching your drawers.
(guard #1) Eyes straight ahead.
- Keep it moving.
- (guard #2) Eyes front.
- (guard #1) Keep it moving. Keep it moving.
- Him.
(guard #1) Get him up. Hit him.
(guard #2) Stay down.
Come on.
Fish. I can't deal with that.
Fish. Come on.
Yo, fish. Fish, you're taking too long, bro.
This ain't gonna fly. The Ricans, we've got
genetically higher blood pressure, you know?
My cousin, he died from too much stress.
You said he was moving in on your girl.
My other cousin,
but thanks for bringing that up.
Look, the good news is I can get to the roof.
- So what happens now?
- Now?
It's all about timing.
(watch beeps)
- It's a top-dollarjob. You know who did it?
- No. Do you?
People who do this kind of work
are ghosts, man.
The guy behind the guy behind the guy,
you know?
Can you see anything that proves
the tape might have been doctored?
The thing's clean. No footprints.
Usually, you peel the video back,
anything bogus comes off.
Now you see it, now you don't.
But not this one.
It's laced. Ingrained.
Whoa, whoa.
- You see something?
- The problem with eyes is they play tricks.
But your ears - ears don't lie.
Here's the audio track from the tape.
- Sounds pretty true?
- Yeah.
But noise is alive.
See, it doesn'tjust die like that.
Stripped down,
those levels should be dancing.
A room that size would give you
a blam, blam, blam, blam, you know.
Off each wall, a split second after the other.
On yours,
the reverb's bouncing at the same time.
- What does that mean?
- The sound of a gunshot.
It wasn't recorded in that room.
- Would you testify to that?
- Oh, uh, I don't know.
The tape's a dupe.
For all I know, you guys tampered with it.
Look, if you want me to testify in court, I'm
gonna need to get my hands on the original.
- (Pope) How are those allergies?
- Excuse me?
- (Pope) In your motion, you cited chronic...
- Sinusitis.
It's not an allergy, actually.
It's a bacterial infection.
The moist air from the river along
the east wall helps keep me, you know...
clear.
I'm impressed. Not even a week here
and you're working it like an old con.
You've got one up on me.
You know why I needed to file those motions,
but I have no idea
why you needed to transfer me.
Traffic control, Scofield.
That's all. Traffic control.
It's coming up on five o'clock. Call it a day.
- I don't think I can do that.
- Why not?
If I let go of this support,
the whole thing's coming down.
See, the Taj was designed using axial force -
a series of internal forces
along the longitudinal axis.
- Yeah. How much longer?
- Depends on how long it takes to dry.
If you need me to leave,
I can show your secretary how to hold it.
You can stay. There'll be a guard outside.
Just check in with Becky
and she'll have somebody escort you back.
- All right.
- And, Scofield.
I wanna thank you for showing up today.
I would've understood it if you didn't.
- We had a deal.
- Right.
Still, thanks. My wife is gonna love it.
You're welcome.
- (man) See you tomorrow, sir.
- (woman) Good night, Warden.
(door closes)
We'd just happen to be two people
who happen to know each other,
who happen to show up at the same movie
theatre at what happens to be the same time.
(woman laughs)
You know, from this angle, you look
just as good as you did when we first met.
- How about from this one?
- Even better.
- Oh.
- Uh-uh. Those are for your guests.
- Guests?
- Your associates.
They said you had a meeting.
They're in the den.
Evening, Warden.
There's nothing I can do. I'm obligated to file
every motion so a hearing can be scheduled.
- And how long does that take?
- A month, maybe two. It's out of my hands.
Why do I feel you're not disappointed?
May I ask you a question, Warden?
More of an observation, really.
I was looking at the morgue photos
from that boy back in Toledo - Will Clayton -
and, my Lord,
if he wasn't the spitting image of his daddy.
The apple fell real far from the tree
with that one, didn't it?
It fell off the tree, fell all over the pavement.
You son of a bitch.
Your wife gave you a pass on the affair,
but that's all the forgiveness she's got left.
Especially when it comes to
an illegitimate child.
What happened with young Will, Warden?
- Get out of my house.
- Lose Scofield's paperwork.
- Are you staying for dinner?
- Thanks, but I think we're on our way.
Judy, it was a real pleasure.
Thank you. And thatjust may have been
the best iced tea I've ever had.
Warden, better do everything you can
to hold on to this one.
- I will.
- Good.
- Is everything all right?
- Oh, yeah. Just fine. I, uh...
I just have a little unfinished work
to take care of. I'll be right in.
OK.
He's all clear.
- Evening, Lincoln.
- Doctor.
I'm supposed to give you
a physical this evening.
Let me apologise for the dose of irony
we're about to participate in.
It's all right. Just doing yourjob.
Yeah, well...
Letting them know you're healthy enough to
execute is not why I went to medical school.
- I apologise.
- It's OK.
All right.
I'm gonna need
a family medical history from you.
Any ailments or conditions
that are hereditary. Let's start with your mom.
- Cancer. Liver.
- OK. Father?
Split when I was young.
Siblings.
Anyone besides Michael?
Fox River's a small town, Lincoln.
People around here don't have
a whole lot to do besides time and talk.
Are you close?
(Linc) We were.
- (Sara) How about now?
- Huh?
How about now?
(Linc) He's been abandoned his whole life.
Dad, Mom - she died young -
and now me.
Think that's why he's here?
Cos your death would feel like
it's happening again
(Linc) I abandoned him a long time ago.
That's why he's here.
- (watch beeps)
- (buzzer)
(guard) Gates closing.
- It's time.
- Time?
Oh, God. Here we go again.
Count's in 15 minutes. What are you doing?
- Trust me. The less you know, the better.
- The less I know? You got me in the dark.
That's exactly where you wanna be.
(man) Don't normally find you here
at this hour.
Are you seeking his forgiveness? Or advice?
I really don't know any more, Ben.
All I know is my son Will
was my responsibility.
- If I'd stayed in his life, I could've saved it.
- His death was an accident, Henry.
He was a criminal,
and an addict, but he was only 18 years old.
His mother made it clear you couldn't be
in his life if you weren't gonna be in hers.
When you chose to stay with Judy,
you understood that.
I not only understood it, I was grateful for it.
I told myself I was respecting her wishes.
I cursed her under my breath
while every day I thanked God
for allowing me to wash my hands of her.
Of Toledo.
All of it.
So I ran home,
to Judy,
and I buried the secret.
But I never got a chance to...
to bury my... my son.
What kind of a person does that, Ben?
Sacrifices somebody else's life
just to make their own life easier.
You can argue with me all night. Believe me,
I haven't got anything better to do.
But it won't change the fact that I can't
just hand out original copies of evidence.
- If you could just take a look...
- I don't care. I can't give it to you.
What if we brought somebody here?
Your supervisor could monitor them.
He'd strip down and swear
on a stack of Bibles. Whatever.
Wait. What did you say
the docket number was?
It's 296 SPE.
- What's wrong?
- Come with me.
Last night a pipe burst upstairs,
flooded the place.
Files from over 100 cases -
pretty much lost all of them, including yours.
- Just this room?
- Some kind of freak accident.
(buzzer)
(whistle)
- (guard) Count 'em.
- (Bellick) Callahan, Knight.
Malinowski, Pohlen.
(watch beeps)
Chance, Graziano.
Scofield, Sucre.
Scofield, get the hell out here.
We got a runner.
(alarm)
(PA) Lockdown.
Lockdown!
(inmates shout)
All right. For the last time, piñata.
Where the hell's Scofield?
He's gone, you're gone. You hear me?
(radio) Call it off, Captain.
I got Scofield right here.
- Where?
- (radio) In the warden's office.
Are you looking at him?
Stop trying to nail the secretary
and check the damn office.
Captain, he's gone.
(alarm continues and dogs bark)
- The man can'tjust vanish.
- I know, sir.
- He never checked out? The rear door?
- Still locked. I checked.
How the hell did he?
- What's going on?
- You're in the warden's office.
I could kill you and the paperwork
wouldn't need more than a date.
- Tell me, what were you doing in here?
- All right, Deputy. That's enough.
The work wasn't dry.
You said to stay until it was.
- You were in here?
- Yes, sir.
- It's true. I never saw him leave.
- I must not have seen him.
This is ridiculous. This prisoner
was out of his cell. He missed the count.
(Pope) I understand, Deputy.
The thing is,
Mr Scofield is not our problem any more.
There was an error in his paperwork.
He's gonna be transferred.
That's not possible.
Escort the prisoner back to his cell.
Warden, all I need is three weeks.
- Get off me!
- Come on!
Henry, please. I just need a little time.
Just give me the time.
Any chance you want to write this off
as a coincidence?
Me neither.
How could they know we were coming?
Three hours ago, we didn't know.
- We're pissing someone off.
- You say that like it's a good thing.
People start breaking the law,
you know you're getting warm.
We still have our copy of the tape, so maybe...
- Nick.
- Stay here.
Whoever it was has gone.
Does it look like they got anything?
No.
Everything's exactly the way I left it.
What? What?
- What?
- The tape. It's gone.
- Are you sure?
- How?
- Think this through.
- How could they know?
- Wait. Does anyone else have a key?
- No.
- Are you sure this is where you put it?
- You were here. I was talking to you.
I walked toward the cabinet, and I said...
What?
Veronica, are you OK?
Veronica.
- (buzzer)
- (Bellick) Open up!
Breakfast, gentlemen. Let's move it.
Sucre, let's go. Scofield, wait here.
I'm sure your ride'll be along any minute now.
This can't be it.
It can't end like this.
(Bellick) Let's move it.
- (Michael) Fitz.
- What?
We were gonna take Fitz out.
It was as clear as day.
And the cops? How long did it take them
to respond? You got all the timing down?
Think we would've made it?
Sucre, now.
(§ "Orange Sky" by Alexi Murdoch)
§ Well, I had a dream
I stood beneath an orange sky
§ Yes, I had a dream
Hey, fish face, where are you going?
§ With my brother standing by
Call my wife. Tell her to get the kids
and get the hell out of the country.
§ I said, brother, you know, you know
§ It's a long road we've been walking on
Sorry.
§ You know it is, you know it is
§ Such a long road we've been walking on
Don't forget to buckle up.
- (Pope) What's he doing out of his cell?
- (guard) He's being transferred.
No, there must be some mistake.
This man filed a motion yesterday.
He has a medical condition
which precludes transfer.
Sinusitis, right?
Sinusitis.
Take the prisoner back to his cell. But yank
his rec time. He missed count last night.
Hey.
You're home early. Everything OK?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
There's just...
Judy,
there's someone I need to tell you about.
- (phone rings)
- (woman) Yes?
- (Kellerman) The transfer did not go through.
- (woman) Disappointing.
- (Kellerman) We can refile, but...
- (woman) It's a waste of time.
I think it's time we stopped
beating around the bush,
and go after the damn bush.
(Kellerman) Burrows.
What do you want done?
(woman) Take the only thing
Burrows has left- time.
After all, the chair isn't the only way
to take a man's life in prison.
Visiontext Subtitles: Jo Clarke
ENGLISH SDH