This is a generated SRT file for testing.
It contains 100 subtitle entries.
This is an example of a
two-line subtitle.
The timing is set to be consistent.
3 seconds on-screen
with a 1-second gap between each entry.
This line tests for italics.
This line tests for bold.
And this one tests for underline.
(Note: Not all players support these tags.)
Testing special characters: &  " '
Testing international characters: é à ç ñ ü
This next line is intentionally very long to see how the video player handles automatic line wrapping or text truncation.
Test Subtitle Entry #12
Test Subtitle Entry #13
Test Subtitle Entry #14
Test Subtitle Entry #15
Test Subtitle Entry #16
Test Subtitle Entry #17
Test Subtitle Entry #18
Test Subtitle Entry #19
Test Subtitle Entry #20
Test Subtitle Entry #21
Test Subtitle Entry #22
Test Subtitle Entry #23
Test Subtitle Entry #24
Test Subtitle Entry #25
Test Subtitle Entry #26
Test Subtitle Entry #27
Test Subtitle Entry #28
Test Subtitle Entry #29
Test Subtitle Entry #30
Test Subtitle Entry #31
Test Subtitle Entry #32
Test Subtitle Entry #33
Test Subtitle Entry #34
Test Subtitle Entry #35
Test Subtitle Entry #36
Test Subtitle Entry #37
Test Subtitle Entry #38
Test Subtitle Entry #39
Test Subtitle Entry #40
Test Subtitle Entry #41
Test Subtitle Entry #42
Test Subtitle Entry #43
Test Subtitle Entry #44
Test Subtitle Entry #45
Test Subtitle Entry #46
Test Subtitle Entry #47
Test Subtitle Entry #48
Test Subtitle Entry #49
Halfway there. Test Subtitle #50
Test Subtitle Entry #51
Test Subtitle Entry #52
Test Subtitle Entry #53
Test Subtitle Entry #54
Test Subtitle Entry #55
Test Subtitle Entry #56
Test Subtitle Entry #57
Test Subtitle Entry #58
Test Subtitle Entry #59
Test Subtitle Entry #60
Test Subtitle Entry #61
Test Subtitle Entry #62
Test Subtitle Entry #63
Test Subtitle Entry #64
Test Subtitle Entry #65
Test Subtitle Entry #66
Test Subtitle Entry #67
Test Subtitle Entry #68
Test Subtitle Entry #69
Test Subtitle Entry #70
Test Subtitle Entry #71
Test Subtitle Entry #72
Test Subtitle Entry #73
Test Subtitle Entry #74
Test Subtitle Entry #75
Test Subtitle Entry #76
Test Subtitle Entry #77
Test Subtitle Entry #78
Test Subtitle Entry #79
Test Subtitle Entry #80
Test Subtitle Entry #81
Test Subtitle Entry #82
Test Subtitle Entry #83
Test Subtitle Entry #84
Test Subtitle Entry #85
Test Subtitle Entry #86
Test Subtitle Entry #87
Test Subtitle Entry #88
Test Subtitle Entry #89
Test Subtitle Entry #90
Test Subtitle Entry #91
Test Subtitle Entry #92
Test Subtitle Entry #93
Test Subtitle Entry #94
Almost at the end.
Test Subtitle Entry #96
Test Subtitle Entry #97
Test Subtitle Entry #98
Test Subtitle Entry #99
End of test file.