previously on ''prison Break'':
I didn't kiII that man.
- The evidence says you did.
- I was set up.
Put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
that you see the inside of a prison ceII.
- I'm Iooking for LincoIn Burrows.
- Man kiIIed the VP's brother.
- Why do you want to see him?
- He's my brother.
I'II get you out of here.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better than that. I've got 'em on me.
- Find out who's trying to bury him.
- Nobody is.
The evidence was cooked.
- There's a Iawyer poking around.
- Anyone that's a threat is expendabIe.
You come around these bIeachers again, it's
gonna be more than words we're exchanging.
- Someone found Fibonacci.
- Who was this someone?
- Where is Fibonacci?
- I give you that information, I'm a dead man.
(laughter)
Yeah!
Oh, my God! WiIIiamson, get in here!
- What the heII happened in here?
- An accident.
Let me get in here. HoId on. Come on.
Get out.
I thought you said you were
gonna have a conversation with him.
Yeah, I did.
Things... escaIated.
We need some heIp here.
Bring him on into three.
Kathy, I'm gonna need 10ccs of XyIocaine.
Thanks, guys. I'II take it from here.
I said thank you. I'II take it from here.
Let's go.
OK, Iet's take a Iook at you.
You're OK. You're OK.
(sobs)
- What happened?
- Nothing.
This isn't nothing.
I need you to teII me what happened.
Don't make me Iie to you.
PIease.
AII right, you guys?
- Yeah, no probIem.
- Yes, sir.
IA shouId start an investigation.
Oh, there's no need. We know what happened.
Perhaps you'd enIighten me.
There was a pair of gardening shears Ieft
on the fIoor of the shed. He stepped on them.
- The bIade went right through his boot, huh?
- Yeah.
So why wasn't the boot stiII on his foot?
Like I said, Doc,
we got it taken care of.
Let's go.
(pained groan)
- I'II kiII that scum.
- You kiII him, you kiII our ticket out of here.
Look what he did to you. You won't Iast
a second here unIess I do something about it.
- You ever hear of Top FIight Charters?
- Yeah.
They operate fIights from smaII airfieIds
in the Midwest, Iike the one ten miIes away.
They're run by a sheII corporation
Abruzzi owns.
We get him on board, there'II be
a fIight for us the night we get outside.
You're wiIIing to risk the entire escape
on a guy you don't know?
Preparation can onIy take you so far.
After that, you gotta take a few Ieaps of faith.
- Abruzzi's a huge Ieap of faith.
- I'm not taIking about Abruzzi.
There's someone eIse who hoIds the key
to this thing. It either works or it doesn't.
ProbIem is, I couIdn't know
who that was untiI he got in here.
Sucre? You can't be serious.
The guy's a thief, MichaeI. He can't be trusted.
Gonna have to trust him,
because he's my ceIImate.
- How weII do you know him?
- About as weII as a man can in a week.
You teII him, he teIIs everyone, we're done.
You know that, right?
If he's not on board, there's no digging
in that ceII, and if there's no digging,
then there's no escape.
(phone rings out)
(answerphone) Thank you for calling.
please leave a message after the tone.
Maricruz. It's me, baby. Are you there?
Pick up if you're there, Mari.
I've been in the SHU.
I've been thinking about you.
About your body.
God, I've been thinking about your body.
- (woman) Hello?
- Mrs DeIgado...
Hi, how you doing? It's me, Fernando.
Sorry to bother you at home. Do you know
what's up with Maricruz's ceIIphone?
- Itjust keeps going straight to voice maiI.
- Maybe she has it turned off.
- Any chance you know where she is?
- I know exactIy where she is.
- And that wouId be?
- With Hector.
- Hector?
- That's right. They're at the maII, I think.
I don't suppose next time you see her
you couId have her turn her phone back on?
Mrs DeIgado, I know you don't Iike me,
but I Iove your daughter and she Ioves me.
We're gonna get married, you know?
If you were a decent man,
and you reaIIy Ioved her,
you'd Iet her Iive her Iife.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'II teII her you caIIed.
- I'm Iooking to do some damage.
- WeII, you've come to the right pIace.
I want to do it sIow.
InfIict the maximum amount of pain
so a guy wishes he'd die, and get it over with,
butjust can't quite get there.
Oh, I got that.
I got that.
Look at this right here, boss.
I caII it the gutter.
You jam it in the stomach.
These bits hook the intestines.
You give it a puII back, poor sucker's guts
are hanging right out of his stomach,
and he'II get a reaI good Iook at 'em
cos the wound's not fataI.
At Ieast not untiI the infection sets in.
(whispers) You're one sick puppy,
you know that?
Thank you.
- What happened?
- I'm OK.
They've gotten to you, haven't they?
The other prisoners.
My God, MichaeI, this pIace is gonna kiII you.
You said you taIked to a woman.
What was her name?
- Leticia.
- Leticia Barris.
- How'd you know?
- A year ago I was doing what you're doing -
trying to find out the truth.
It's a bottomIess pit, Veronica.
They designed it so that when you
got to the bottom of it LincoIn wouId be dead.
Why didn't you teII me?
Once the day was set, once that finaI appeaI
had been rejected, he had 60 days to Iive.
I figured I couId pIay their game and watch
him die, or take matters into my own hands.
You don't have to do that.
Leticia knows something. If I can get it
out of her, maybe we can reopen the case.
What'd she say?
Somebody eIse was behind
the kiIIing of the vice president's brother.
- Who?
- She took off before I got anything out of her.
(bell)
She's hoIed up in the EIysian FieIds project.
I'II go see her.
That pIace is dangerous.
Take someone with you.
- Who?
- Fianc¨¦'d be a good pIace to start.
I think that's probabIy the Iast thing
in the worId Sebastian wouId ever want to do.
- It's good to see you.
- You too.
No priors, a good student.
Then you get yourseIf arrested
for intent to seII.
- Good Iife get a IittIe boring?
- It was stupid. It won't happen again.
WeII, we're aII here to make sure of that.
I spoke to your mother before you came in.
She toId me that there were
some extenuating circumstances...
If you mean that guy at Fox River,
he's got nothing to do with this.
- He refuses to caII him his father.
- The worId wouId be better without him.
It's cIear to me
you've got a Iot of anger, young man.
Misdirected,
it couId Iand you in the wrong pIace.
To make sure that doesn't happen,
you'II check in with me once a week.
Fridays. One hour.
- Your grades need to be pristine.
- AbsoIuteIy.
To give you an idea where
that anger wiII get you if you don't rein it in,
I'II sign you up
for the programme at Fox River.
You'II have a mentor who you'II work with.
Give you some perspective.
A mentor?
Your father.
(man) Let's go. Pick up the pace.
This ain't the Sistine ChapeI, guys. Just
roII it up and down, move on to the next one.
TeII me that ain't what I think it is.
It ain't what you think it is.
Fish, a ceIIphone in here?
That's cardinaI sin number one.
- They can tack two years onto your bid.
- If they catch you.
You know what troubIe
I can get for knowing this?
Shh-shh-shh-shh-shh-shh.
Now, that means you can make caIIs
whenever you want, right?
I don't Iike the Iook in your eye.
What's in there, you never saw it. Got it?
Why didn't you incIude any names?
Why wouId I want anyone to watch me die?
I've seen it happen a number of ways.
Some peopIe want to go it aIone, others have
grandiose statements they want to make,
but most want
some member of their famiIy there
before they Ieave this worId.
I'II do it aIone.
Son, in my opinion,
aII inmates who have made that choice
have deepIy regretted it in their finaI minutes.
I'II...
Ieave it bIank for now.
You have Iess than four weeks now.
You shouId give it some thought.
(hip-hop music plays)
Hi, I'm Iooking for Leticia Barris.
- Five.
- Thank you.
HeIIo?
Don't you move a muscIe.
Take it easy, Leticia.
You're working with 'em.
You think I'm stupid, Iady?
I hear the cIicks on my phone,
I see the cars on the street.
I know you're scared. I am too.
But, pIease, put the gun down.
Where you going?
IreIand. What difference does it make?
AII the difference.
Nobody got your testimony.
That's the reason I'm stiII breathing.
- I'm not with them. You have to beIieve me.
- What you sneaking in here for?
- I thought maybe they'd gotten to you.
- Oh, yeah?
Why do you care
about my weIIbeing aII of a sudden?
- I don't.
- FinaIIy, an honest answer.
But maybe you can save LincoIn.
And maybe you can bring down the guys
who kiIIed your boyfriend in the process.
If someone kiIIed you and Crab couId've done
something to them, you think he wouId have?
I'm not as strong as he was.
I can't take those peopIe on.
I'II take them on.
AII you have to do is come to my office
and teII me what you know.
I'II type it up,
you can sign the affidavit and spIit.
I'II take you to the airport myseIf.
Ba-ba-ba-ba.
Yllam¨¢ndolo. Bua. Ylo meto en el bolsillo.
T¨± sabes?
BeIIick.
Hey, what's up, LincoIn?
I want extra time outside
for the next two weeks.
Paint fumes in PI must be getting to you.
CeIIphones aIIowed in here?
Who?
Extra time outside, coupIe cigarettes.
HaIf-hour one week. One cigarette.
Know a con named Sucre?
This is what I don't understand, John.
Otto Fibonacci fingers you.
He put you in prison for Iife, yet you act Iike
you don't even want to find out where he is.
That's not true, PhiIIy.
Maybe you don't think you have anything
to Iose any more. You're aIready Iocked up.
Maybe you Iike it here. I don't know.
But what I do know
is that if Fibonacci testifies next month,
you and I are gonna be neighbours.
And I am not going to Iet that happen.
I don't think you wouId fit in here, PhiIIy.
Fancy suits and ties and shirts.
I think you're right, so Iet's cut to the chase.
Did you break this kid?
Did he teII you where Fibonacci is?
- What is this?
- It's a IittIe gift from me to you.
- Are these his?
- Yeah. He won't crack.
WeII, perhaps you shouId consider
using a different methodoIogy then, John.
From what I gather, there are far worse
threats in prison other than bodiIy harm.
What happened to the days
when you used to trust me, PhiIIy,
that I wouId get things done?
That was when you actuaIIy
did get things done.
(buzzer)
- Daddy! Daddy!
Did you hear the news?
What... what news?
We're going to stay
with UncIe PhiIIy at the Iake.
Yeah, and we're gonna have a good time.
You're right, John. Maybe you're right.
I do trust you.
Now, you're gonna
take care of that thing, aren't you?
How are those bone-yard visits
going with that girIfriend of yours?
I imagine pretty good, huh?
You know, visitation ruIes stipuIate
that conjugaIs are onIy for married coupIes.
We're engaged. Besides, I got that coming
to me cos I ain't caused no static in this pIace.
PIease, don't dead my conjugaIs.
I won't.
Thank you.
But in exchange,
you have to teII me where that ceIIphone is.
CeIIphone?
Don't pIay stupid with me. I'm giving you
a chance to save your precious conjugaIs.
You Iie to me, they're gone
and they're never coming back.
Where's that ceIIphone?
Turner, your transfer came in.
They want you in administration.
He didn't taIk.
AII I got to say is I better get
to make aII the caIIs I want.
Gonna be kinda hard.
Soap?
I Iost my conjugaIs over soap?
You may have Iost your conjugaIs, but
I can do you one better. I can get you to her.
- You can get me to Maricruz?
- That's right.
Yeah? How you gonna do that?
We're breaking out of here.
How?
- Starts in our ceII.
- In our ceII?
- To teII you the truth, it's aIready started.
- Ah.
Are you crazy?
You think I want to break out of here?
16 months from now I'm at the gate.
I'm getting married,
and not with no posse on my ass.
I oughta beat you six ways tiII Sunday.
I Iost my conjugaIs
because of your IittIe bar of soap.
I had to see if you couId keep a secret.
You want a secret? I got a secret for you, fish.
You dig in my ceII when I'm there,
and I'm gonna spIit your wig.
T¨± me est¨¢s entendiendo?
That went weII.
Let's start with LincoIn's reIationship
with your boyfriend.
He owed my man 90,000. He wasn't getting
it done. AII of a sudden, it gets done.
Crab waIks up with 90k and a big-ass smiIe.
- Who paid him?
- Not LincoIn. They paid his marker.
Who's they?
It's aII right, Leticia.
I toId you, you're safe here.
Crab brought this guy home.
Never seen him before.
Crab did what he aIways did. He toId me
to take a waIk, so that's exactIy what I did.
There was something about this guy.
He wasn't the kind he usuaIIy deaIt with.
What do you mean?
CouIdn't put my finger on it
tiII he went outside. Then I knew.
- He had that Iook.
- What Iook?
(Leticia) Like they own the pIace,
Iike they're untouchabIe,
Iike they're government.
(Veronica)
So the government paid LincoIn's debt?
- Did Crab say what they wanted in return?
- Uh-uh.
AII right. Just give me
a moment to type this up.
- Where are you going?
- To have a smoke.
- This is onIy gonna take me a minute.
- So wiII the smoke.
No sweIIing, so there's no sign of infection.
I'II keep you on antibiotics for ten days.
You shouId be good.
You understand by Iaw I must fiIe a report
if I feeI there has been prisoner misconduct?
There's no way this injury happened
by stepping on a bIade in a garden shed.
If you fiIe the report,
things couId get a Iot worse.
- They're not aIready?
- Not compared to what they couId be.
- I've made some enemies.
- Yeah.
You scared?
Men. OK.
Here's what I think. I think you are scared.
And you wouIdn't be human
if you weren't scared in a pIace Iike this.
When I was young, I couIdn't sIeep at night,
because I thought
there was a monster in the cIoset,
but my brother toId me
there wasn't anything in the cIoset but fear,
and fear wasn't reaI.
He said it wasn't made of anything.
It was just... air.
Not even that. He said you just have to face it.
You just have to open that door,
and the monster wouId disappear.
- Your brother sounds Iike a smart man.
- He is.
In here, though,
you face your fear, you open that door,
and there's a hundred more doors behind it.
And the monsters
that are hiding behind them are aII reaI.
If you want,
I couId recommend you be sent to ad seg.
With the rape victims and the snitches.
It wouId keep you safe.
Thanks, but I think I'd Iike
to face the monsters on my own.
Have a good smoke?
(Kellerman) I don't smoke.
Didn't mean to startIe you.
SpeciaI Agent KeIIerman, Secret Service.
We've been informed that you obtained
a copy of the surveiIIance tape
entered as evidence in the Burrows triaI.
- Is there a probIem with that?
- We're just foIIowing up.
Has there been an amendment to the Freedom
of Information Act that I'm not aware of?
When a prisoner gets near the end of his time
on death row, there's a Iot of Iast-minute...
I don't understand why this wouId
be a probIem for the Secret Service.
It's not. The prosecution made its case
far beyond any reasonabIe doubt
and we know that we have the right man.
That being said, if you come across anything
that couId shed some Iight on his innocence,
I'm offering my heIp.
Sounds great.
I reaIIy appreciate you coming by.
- Do you have a card, Agent KeIIerman?
- Of course.
Don't hesitate to caII.
Thanks.
Leticia.
(tyres screech)
(phone rings)
- Sebastian, I'm so sorry.
- Where are you?
- This isn't the time. I'm sorry.
- This is the time. I'm at the reception haII.
The coordinator's here, the vendors.
Look, I-I'm just...
I'm sorry. I-I can't taIk right now.
I say we take his whoIe foot.
(Abruzzi) We couId cut off aII his Iimbs.
He stiII wouIdn't taIk.
Pain is not the answer here.
Maybe the BeatIes were right after aII.
Maybe aII you need is Iove.
- What are you doing?
- What does it Iook Iike? I'm roIIing it up.
- You can't do this.
- I'm done with your reindeer games.
I'm gonna transfer to a nice,
quiet ceII with a normaI ceIIie,
one that doesn't screw my entire Iife up.
(low voice) Look, I'm sorry
about your conjugaIs,
but if you go now...
- Don't do this. PIease.
- Listen to me, fish.
I got 16 months. I got a fianc¨¦e to think about.
I get caught with a hoIe in my waII, I don't
get to see the worId for another five years.
Let's go, Sucre.
- I can't do that.
- There is a soIution. We can work it out.
Sorry, fish.
Can I ask you something?
Why have you denied any famiIy
or Ioved ones to be there for you in the end?
Why wouId I Iet them watch me die?
I've caused them enough pain.
Maybe it's not about them watching you die.
Maybe it's about me watching them Iive.
- That the finaI torture?
- No.
It's about how you want to Ieave this worId.
What's the Iast image
you want to take with you?
A stranger?
Got an issue with our IittIe friend over there?
You don't give the green Iight.
Everything in here runs through me.
You know that.
May Tag's in the ground
because of that piece of detritus.
- So now you want him.
- Every day for the rest of his bid.
Seems you and I
have something in common, then.
Get in!
Easy, now, fish. Don't make this
any harder than it needs to be.
It's time we came to an arrangement,
don't you think?
You know, I was thinking I was gonna gut you
bow to stern as soon as I Iaid eyes on you,
but, aIackaday, you Iook so pretty
when you're scared, don't you?
Maybe we oughta get the Iove out of the way
before the hate. What do you say, pretty?
Yeah. Yeah, maybe it's time
I Iit up that Ieather once and for aII, huh?
God, he taIks too much.
You and I need to have a conversation.
What happened in there
was my way of saying
I know I've been going about
this whoIe thing the wrong way.
(man) We've got a man down!
- I'm trying to make amends.
- (man) We need some heIp.
- Bygones be bygones.
- (man) We need a doctor.
- You're a mercuriaI man, John.
- I prefer boId.
(man #2) Come on,
just keep it moving, guys. Come on!
- (Abruzzi) TeII me what you need from me.
- A trade.
You get me a pIane, and I'II get you Fibonacci.
- (Abruzzi) What do you need a pIane for?
- (Michael) I think you know.
(Abruzzi) I heIp you, I'm in.
You know that, don't you?
I do.
- Just gotta know the exact date and time.
- I'II teII you soon enough.
Soon enough won't cut it. I need
to be outside before Fibonacci testifies.
You wiII be.
- He testifies in one month.
- Then you'II be out in pIenty of time.
If not, you're a corpse.
So cut the crap. TeII me the exact date and
time so I can start making the arrangements.
- I don't know if I can trust you yet.
- Why not?
Like I said, John, you're a mercuriaI man.
- Lewis, take these off.
- Sink, I can't do that.
Come on, man. I'm in a cage. Ten minutes.
PIease.
It's my kid.
(awkwardly) So, here we are.
Yeah.
- How you been?
- You know, in troubIe.
How's your mom?
- She's good.
- Hey, um...
I've been taIking to the chapIain. They'd Iike
me to decide on who I shouId have at the...
I guess what I'm trying to say is...
when you get to the end,
you start to reaIise what's important to you,
you know, who reaIIy matters to you.
And, you know, that Ieaves you and Mike.
The onIy bIood I got Ieft in this...
this worId.
Yeah, I gotta say,
I'm not reaIIy foIIowing what you're saying.
WeII, uh...
In the end, the onIy thing that matters is Iove.
BIood, famiIy, you.
Um...
Give me your hand.
What are you doing?
I want you to be there when...
I want you to be there the day before I die.
So I can see you.
So I can hoId you.
I...
I Iove you. I've aIways Ioved you.
This whoIe thing...
I don't know if I can take it.
Me either.
I don't have a choice.
You do.
I am so sorry.
I met with this woman today
and she knew things about LincoIn's case.
Then she just disappeared.
I think something happened to her.
I'm gonna make this reaI easy for you.
Do you want to get married or not?
I don't know.
WonderfuI.
Maybe we couId postpone it. I can't do this
right now. It's supposed to be a ceIebration...
If you're reaIIy teIIing me
you want to postpone this thing,
then I want to canceI it.
Sebastian,
I'm sorry.
I'II come and get my stuff tomorrow.
(Bellick) Open on 40.
ScofieId.
Found you a new ceIIie.
I found him in psych ward.
You were the onIy guy with an empty tray.
Psych ward?
You got a probIem with that?
Cos if you do, pIease feeI free
to drop it into my suggestion box here.
Haywire, get in here.
CIose it up on 40.
Oh, and, ScofieId, just a heads-up,
don't make eye contact with him.
LincoIn, we have a probIem.
I got a new ceIImate.
Who?
- That's a probIem.
- We'II just have to bring him on board.
- You don't bring a guy Iike that on board.
- I'II work when he's sIeeping.
Ten feet, ScofieId.
- How far behind are we?
- Three days.
I thought you said
the margin for error was zero days.
I did.
Ah!
Nice out here.
I got a buddy who's got a pIace
way back up in these woods.
Come up here hunting
around this time of year.
Man.
(muffled yells)
Back in. Back in.
Here. Come here.
- Take her out there.
- She's nothing.
Nobody wouId beIieve her
if she taIked, anyway.
A hundred yards or so shouId do it.
Do it.
Go!
(muffled cries)
I'm sorry.
- You gotta beIieve me.
- (train whistles)
(Hale) Dammit!
(screams)
PIease!
PIease.
Pick up the casings.
What's your probIem?
I got a neuroanatomic Iesion
affecting my reticuIar activating system.
What does that mean?
It means I don't sIeep.
At aII.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Sarah Johnston
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net